techshout.com 2018-12-26

# Privacy - TechShout

The terms ‘TechShout.com’ and ‘www.TechShout.com’ are used in this document (or Agreement) to refer to the Web site itself. Privacy issues are a high priority for us at www.TechShout.com and we follow standard industry practices to maintain your personal information. Please read the following to learn more about our privacy policy.

TechShout.com does not spam or sell/lease its user information to third parties.

 **Policy Coverage**

This Privacy Policy covers TechShout.com’s treatment of personally identifiable information that TechShout.com collects when you are on the www.TechShout.com site, and when you use TechShout.com’s services. This policy also covers TechShout.com’s treatment of any personally identifiable information that TechShout.com’s business partners share with TechShout.com. This policy does not apply to the practices of companies that TechShout.com does not own or control, or to people that TechShout.com does not employ or manage.  
Personal Information Collected by TechShout.com

 **ONLINE REGISTRATION** : In order to become a TechShout.com member, you must first create a member account on TechShout.com by providing information about yourself including but not limited to name, email address, country, ZIP/postal code, birth date, a brief summary of yourself and a password. TechShout.com checks for the validity of the email addresses.

 **OPTIONAL PROFILE INFORMATION** : Once you provide the basic information to create an account, you will have the opportunity to provide additional information in the Profile section describing your skills, interests, professional and academic background and favorites. Provision of this additional information beyond what is required at registration is entirely optional; it allows you to better identify yourself and create superior networking opportunities with others through shared contexts. but enables you to better identify yourself and find new opportunities on TechShout.com. Your Profile information can only be viewed by other TechShout.com visitors or registered members or members of your personal network only depending on the option you choose.

 **RECOGNIZING YOU AS A TechShout.com MEMBER** : For TechShout.com to recognize you as a registered member, you must login with your login email and password. At the time of login, you will have the option to instruct the site to remember you so when you come back the next time to use TechShout.com, you would not have to login with your email and password. As is common in the industry, TechShout.com uses the technology of cookies and site log files to monitor user registration, to recognize registered members when they revisit the site and to track site usage. Our ability to identify you as a registered member allows us to customize the TechShout.com experience and to protect your personal information based on your account settings.

 **INTERNET COMMUNICATION PROTOCOL INFORMATION** : The communication standards of the Internet industry transmit the URL of the site from which you visit www.TechShout.com, the IP address of your computer, the IP address of your ISP, various attributes of your computer such as operating system, resolution and browser software, and the date and time of your various requests for pages on www.TechShout.com. TechShout.com file logging system automatically logs all of this information in its log files for its analysis.

 **NEWSLETTER SUBSCRIPTIONS** : Visitors to TechShout.com may also sign up with their name and email address for a variety of newsletters that TechShout.com produces with varying frequency (e.g., News headlines) without having to register. TechShout.com confirms the subscription by sending an email to the email address specified before sending the newsletter.

 **USE OF INFORMATION BY TechShout.com**

TechShout.com is an online website that offers a variety of services designed to connect people from around the world. The information, whether personal information of any form of self-expression is used to help you describe yourself to other users. TechShout.com also collects additional information in order to operate and improve our service. www.TechShout.com is the sole owner of the information collected on the TechShout.com site.

 **VISIBILITY OF PUBLIC CREATIVE CONTRIBUTIONS** : TechShout.com provides a variety of forums for its members to express themselves in the form of articles, columns, opinions, comments, reviews, art and photographs. Since this expression is linked to the member’s identity and the expression is in the public domain, the compilation of a member’s creative contributions to TechShout.com will be visible to all visitors of TechShout.com whether or not they are registered members of TechShout.com.

 **VISIBILITY OF PRIVATE MESSAGES WITHIN NETWORK** : You will be able to create and share messages within your personal network. The visibility of these private notes will be restricted to your network unless you or one of the members in your network choose to forward it to others within or outside www.TechShout.com.

 **SHARING OF INFORMATION WITH THIRD PARTIES** : TechShout.com takes your privacy very seriously. TechShout.com will never sell, rent, or otherwise provide your personally identifiable information to any third parties unless it is to carry out your instructions and to provide specific services. As an example, we send your information to a credit card processing company to process a payment you have made for the use of a TechShout.com service. These third parties are bound by strict confidentiality agreements which limit their use of such information. In addition, TechShout.com may share your information to send direct mailers or complimentary coupons/offers to a mailing agency to process postal mailing. Again, such an agency would be bound by strict confidentiality agreements that limit their use of such information.

 **EMAIL COMMUNICATIONS** : TechShout.com generally communicates with you as a registered member of TechShout.com through the primary email that you have specified at the time of registration. This is also used as the login text string in conjunction with the password to authenticate you on the www.TechShout.com site. Your email and password are never shared with anybody within or outside TechShout.com. TechShout.com uses this email address to send you three types of communications:

Sending you emails related to the proper functioning of your account (e.g. when you receive a response to a classified you have posted on TechShout.com or when you receive an invitation to join the personal network of another person). Sending you newsletters that you have subscribed to. Sending you occasional announcements about changes in TechShout.com’s policies or promotions introduction of new services. Please note that these email communications may contain commercial messages of advertisers; however, TechShout.com does not provide your personal information or emails to any of the advertisers; we just include the advertising banners they provide us in the emails that we send. As always you can opt out of the newsletters or promotional announcements.

 **PARTNERING WITH OTHERS** : TechShout.com may partner with other online services to offer a combined service. Whenever we offer such combined services, TechShout.com will make it clear who the partner is and it will be entirely up to you to use or not to use the service. Where any personal information is passed along to the partner you will be informed prior to that sharing.

 **PROVISION OF AGGREGATE DEMOGRAPHIC INFORMATION TO THIRD PARTIES** : TechShout.com reserves the right to provide aggregate demographic information of its member base to advertisers and others so as to attract pertinent advertisers to advertise on TechShout.com. We do not shared personal information of individual users with advertisers.

 **COMMUNICATIONS TO OTHERS FROM YOU THROUGH TechShout.com** : You will be able to send emails to others — members and non-members — through the TechShout.com system. For example, you may send a comment on an article written by another member. Or you may send an email invitation to a non-member to join your personal network. In these instances, these emails will list your name and email address in the header of the message. The recipients of these emails initiated by you will get to know your name and email address. TechShout.com is not responsible for how these recipients use this information. Your contact information will only be shared with another member only if both of you indicated you would like to establish contact with each other.

 **COMMUNICATIONS FROM OTHERS TO YOU THROUGH TechShout.com** : Only registered members of TechShout.com are allowed to communicate with you through TechShout.com through a form on TechShout.com. Unless and until you respond to this email, they will not get to know your email address. You may, however, choose an account setting that prevents any other member from contacting you or inviting you to join their personal network.

 **DISCLOSURES REQUIRED BY LAW** : It is possible that we may need to disclose personal information when required by law. We will disclose such information wherein we have a good-faith belief that it is necessary to comply with a court order, ongoing judicial proceeding, or other legal process served on our company or to exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims.

### Cookie Policy for TechShout

This is the Cookie Policy for TechShout, accessible from www.techshout.com

 **What Are Cookies**

As is common practice with almost all professional websites this site uses cookies, which are tiny files that are downloaded to your computer, to improve your experience. This page describes what information they gather, how we use it and why we sometimes need to store these cookies. We will also share how you can prevent these cookies from being stored however this may downgrade or ‘break’ certain elements of the sites functionality.

For more general information on cookies see the Wikipedia article on HTTP Cookies.

 **How We Use Cookies**

We use cookies for a variety of reasons detailed below. Unfortunately in most cases there are no industry standard options for disabling cookies without completely disabling the functionality and features they add to this site. It is recommended that you leave on all cookies if you are not sure whether you need them or not in case they are used to provide a service that you use.

 **Disabling Cookies**

You can prevent the setting of cookies by adjusting the settings on your browser (see your browser Help for how to do this). Be aware that disabling cookies will affect the functionality of this and many other websites that you visit. Disabling cookies will usually result in also disabling certain functionality and features of the this site. Therefore it is recommended that you do not disable cookies.

 **The Cookies We Set**

  * Account related cookiesIf you create an account with us then we will use cookies for the management of the signup process and general administration. These cookies will usually be deleted when you log out however in some cases they may remain afterwards to remember your site preferences when logged out.
  * Login related cookiesWe use cookies when you are logged in so that we can remember this fact. This prevents you from having to log in every single time you visit a new page. These cookies are typically removed or cleared when you log out to ensure that you can only access restricted features and areas when logged in.
  * Email newsletters related cookiesThis site offers newsletter or email subscription services and cookies may be used to remember if you are already registered and whether to show certain notifications which might only be valid to subscribed/unsubscribed users.
  * Surveys related cookiesFrom time to time we offer user surveys and questionnaires to provide you with interesting insights, helpful tools, or to understand our user base more accurately. These surveys may use cookies to remember who has already taken part in a survey or to provide you with accurate results after you change pages.
  * Forms related cookiesWhen you submit data to through a form such as those found on contact pages or comment forms cookies may be set to remember your user details for future correspondence.
  * Site preferences cookiesIn order to provide you with a great experience on this site we provide the functionality to set your preferences for how this site runs when you use it. In order to remember your preferences we need to set cookies so that this information can be called whenever you interact with a page is affected by your preferences.

 **Third Party Cookies**

In some special cases we also use cookies provided by trusted third parties. The following section details which third party cookies you might encounter through this site.

  * This site uses Google Analytics which is one of the most widespread and trusted analytics solution on the web for helping us to understand how you use the site and ways that we can improve your experience. These cookies may track things such as how long you spend on the site and the pages that you visit so we can continue to produce engaging content.For more information on Google Analytics cookies, see the official Google Analytics page.
  * Third party analytics are used to track and measure usage of this site so that we can continue to produce engaging content. These cookies may track things such as how long you spend on the site or pages you visit which helps us to understand how we can improve the site for you.
  * From time to time we test new features and make subtle changes to the way that the site is delivered. When we are still testing new features these cookies may be used to ensure that you receive a consistent experience whilst on the site whilst ensuring we understand which optimisations our users appreciate the most.
  * As we sell products it’s important for us to understand statistics about how many of the visitors to our site actually make a purchase and as such this is the kind of data that these cookies will track. This is important to you as it means that we can accurately make business predictions that allow us to monitor our advertising and product costs to ensure the best possible price.
  * The Google AdSense service we use to serve advertising uses a DoubleClick cookie to serve more relevant ads across the web and limit the number of times that a given ad is shown to you.For more information on Google AdSense see the official Google AdSense privacy FAQ.
  * We use adverts to offset the costs of running this site and provide funding for further development. The behavioural advertising cookies used by this site are designed to ensure that we provide you with the most relevant adverts where possible by anonymously tracking your interests and presenting similar things that may be of interest.
  * Several partners advertise on our behalf and affiliate tracking cookies simply allow us to see if our customers have come to the site through one of our partner sites so that we can credit them appropriately and where applicable allow our affiliate partners to provide any bonus that they may provide you for making a purchase.
  * We also use social media buttons and/or plugins on this site that allow you to connect with your social network in various ways. For these to work the following social media sites including; {List the social networks whose features you have integrated with your site?:12}, will set cookies through our site which may be used to enhance your profile on their site or contribute to the data they hold for various purposes outlined in their respective privacy policies.

 **Opt Out**

 ** ** If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

If you prefer not to receive interest-based content and ads enabled by Quantcast, you can opt-out by clicking on the “Opt Out” link at either Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) [(http://optout.networkadvertising.org/#/](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/#/)) or Digital Advertising Alliance’s (DAA) (<http://optout.aboutads.info/#/>) . Quantcast is a member of the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) and participate in the Digital Advertising Alliance’s (DAA) Self-Regulatory Program. Each of these programs provides an opt-out feature where consumers can choose not to receive targeted advertising from any NAI or DAA affiliate. These links will take you to the NAI opt out (<http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>) and the DAA opt out (<http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>) . If you are located in the European Union, you may prefer to use the EDAA opt out ([http://www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)) . After you opt-out, Quantcast will place a cookie on your browser that identifies you as having opted out. Then you will not receive interest-based content or advertisements enabled by Quantcast and Quantcast will not log your pattern of website visits or other online media consumption. Because the opt-out is cookie-based, your browser must be set to accept third party cookies. If you use multiple devices or browsers, you’ll have to opt out on each. If you delete the cookie, you will need to opt-out again.

 **More Information**

Hopefully that has clarified things for you and as was previously mentioned if there is something that you aren’t sure whether you need or not it’s usually safer to leave cookies enabled in case it does interact with one of the features you use on our site.

However if you are still looking for more information then you can contact us through one of our preferred contact methods:

  * By visiting this link: <https://www.techshout.com/contact-us/>
